[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to
您好，欢迎来到
lesson 3 of this massive open online course
大规模在线公开课程的第3课
on Lambdas and streams JDK 8. In this lesson
在Lambda和流JDK 8上。
we're going be looking at some more advanced concepts around Lambda
我们将围绕Lambda研究一些更高级的概念
expressions and stream API.
表达式和流API。
My name Simon Ritter and I am a Java Technology Evangelist
我叫Simon Ritter，我是Java技术的传播者
In terms of the agenda
就议程而言
for this particular lesson, we're going to start with looking at
在本节课中，我们将从
reductions because reductions
减少，因为减少
are a way of creating a result from a set of
是从一组结果创建结果的方法
data which is the stream and we need to understand
数据是流，我们需要了解
how to use those correctly in order to get the kind
如何正确使用那些以得到那种
results we're looking for, especially when we're trying to take a functional
我们正在寻找的结果，尤其是当我们尝试采用函数
approach.
方法。
This is one of the things that, as Java programmers,
作为Java程序员，这是其中的一件事，
we need to think a little bit differently, so we'll talk about that.
我们需要有所不同，所以我们将对此进行讨论。
We are then going to talk about finite and
然后，我们将讨论有限和
infinite streams because again, being Java programmers, we tend to think in
无限流，因为再次，作为Java程序员，我们倾向于思考
loops
循环
and when we have to deal with an infinite stream we
当我们必须处理无限流时
tend to think about, how do we break out of that stream
倾向于思考，我们如何突围
and it's not actually the case that we break out of the stream,
实际上，我们并没有真正摆脱这种情况，
but we can terminate an infinite stream. So we'll talk about the differences
但我们可以终止无限流。所以我们将讨论差异
and the two types of streams and the approaches you can take.
以及两种类型的信息流以及您可以采用的方法。
Then we'll look at where you should use the forEach method,
然后，我们看一下您应该在哪里使用forEach方法，
but also where you shouldn't use forEach method. There are some
而且您不应该使用forEach方法。有一些
very valid places where you can use that particular method,
您可以使用该特定方法的非常有效的地方，
but there are also a number of places where you can fall into a
但是在很多地方您都可以陷入
trap of still thinking, because it
还在思考的陷阱，因为它
still thinking loops, as you would do in Java and
仍然在思考循环，就像您在Java和
then trying to apply that by thinking, I'll use forEach
然后尝试通过思考来应用，我将使用forEach
for that and not doing it correctly. We'll look at some things you can do to avoid that.
为此，并且没有正确执行。我们将研究一些可以避免这种情况的事情。
We will talk about collectors, which is quite a big subject,
我们将谈论收藏家，这是一个很大的话题，
and so I've created particular section on that. So we can look at different kinds of
因此，我在此上创建了特别的部分。所以我们可以看看不同种类的
collectors,
收藏家
different approaches you can take for gathering the data and
您可以采用不同的方法来收集数据，并且
forming a collection from the results. We're going to look at
从结果中形成一个集合。我们将要看
parallel streams because this is one of the great
并行流，因为这是伟大的之一
advantages of using the stream API is the fact that you can switch from
使用流API的优势在于您可以从
sequential processing to parallel processing
从顺序处理到并行处理
without any change the way your code actually works.
无需更改您的代码实际工作方式。
But the trap you can fall into with this is to think,
但是您可能会陷入的陷阱是：
ah, well, I can just always use a parallel streams and it's
嗯，嗯，我总是可以使用并行流，
always going to do things more quickly. But that's not
总是会更快地做事。但这不是
necessarily the case, so we need to understand where you should use parallel
必然是这样，所以我们需要了解您应该在哪里使用并行
streams and where it's actually less efficient
流以及实际上效率较低的地方
to use a parallel stream rather than a sequential stream. We'll
使用并行流而不是顺序流。好
look at how to debug streams and Lambdas because
看一下如何调试流和Lambda，因为
one of the things about streams API is it does tend to hide quite a lot of the work from
关于流API的一件事是，它的确掩盖了很多工作
you.
您。
So it makes the code look very simple, but when you want to start looking at how to
因此，它使代码看起来非常简单，但是当您要开始研究如何
analyze what's actually happening with the code sometimes you need to take
分析有时需要使用的代码实际发生的情况
some slightly different approaches
一些略有不同的方法
and so we'll look at that. Since this is the last lesson
所以我们来看一下。因为这是最后一课
in the course we'll wrap up everything at the end with some conclusions
在课程中，我们将总结所有的结论
about the whole Lambdas side of things and streams API
关于事物和流API的整个Lambdas方面
and what you can do next in terms of learning about how to use those.
以及在学习如何使用它们方面下一步可以做什么。
Let's start
开始吧
with section 1: Understanding and using
与第1节：了解和使用
reductions.
减少。
What we have to start with is a simple problem
我们首先要解决一个简单的问题
and this was one that we used for training course
这是我们用于培训课程的
that we gave on Lambda and streams when they first came out
当它们初次出现时，我们在Lambda和溪流上提供的
and the question was, how to find the length
问题是，如何找到长度
of the longest line in a file. This is the solution that
文件中最长行的长度。这是解决方案
we provided. You start off with finding that Path
我们提供了。您首先要找到该路径
of the file that you want to read the lines of text from.
您要从中读取文本行的文件。
Then using that
然后用那个
you can use the static method on the Files class,
您可以在Files类上使用静态方法，
which we saw in Lesson 2 and
我们在第2课中看到了
what this allows us to do is to extract the lines of
这允许我们做的是提取
text from the file and provide it as a stream.
文件中的文本，并将其作为流提供。
So our output stream, our stream source is a set of
所以我们的输出流，我们的流源是一组
lines of text being read from the file. We pass that
从文件中读取的文本行。我们通过了
to mapToInt and that will create a
到mapToInt，这将创建一个
stream of integer values using the Lambda expression here,
在这里使用Lambda表达式的整数值流，
which is method reference, simply to say give us the
这是方法参考，只是说给我们
length of each of the strings on the input stream.
输入流中每个字符串的长度。
We pass that to max,
我们将其传递给max
which then obviously reduces it to a single value, which is the biggest
然后显然会将其减小为单个值，这是最大的
integer in the input stream. The length
输入流中的整数。长度
of the longest line in the file. Since that will return an
文件中最长行的长度。由于那将返回一个
Optional,
可选的，
because we may not have any lines in our file, we then
因为我们的文件中可能没有任何行，所以我们
use getAsInt to extract result. So we're assuming
使用getAsInt提取结果。所以我们假设
there is some data there and we would get a value as integer
那里有一些数据，我们将得到一个整数值
and that solves the problem. So you can see
这样就解决了问题。这样你就可以看到
it's fairly straightforward, doesn't require a lot of code
这非常简单，不需要很多代码
and has a very functional approach to it.
并且具有非常实用的方法
Somebody then said to me, well that's nice, but how do we change the problem
然后有人对我说，很好，但是我们如何改变问题
slightly.
略。
How about if we say rather than finding the length of the longest
如果我们说而不是找到最长的长度怎么办
line in the file what if we want to find the actual longest line in a
文件中的行如果要在
file and it's very sensible question.
文件，这是一个非常明智的问题。
So, I had to think about this and I thought, ok,
所以，我不得不考虑这一点，然后我想，
how do we approach this to get the result?
我们如何处理这个问题以获得结果？
The problem is really because being a Java programmer
问题确实是因为作为Java程序员
I tend to think in loops and I tend to think in terms of state.
我倾向于以循环的方式思考，而倾向于以状态的方式思考。
So I would think to myself I need to keep a record of the longest line that I've
所以我想我自己需要记录我最长的记录
read from the file so far
到目前为止从文件中读取
and then use that until I've read all the lines in the file.
然后使用它，直到我阅读了文件中的所有行。
But I can't do that so I need a functional approach.
但是我做不到，所以我需要一种实用的方法。
This is what I call the naive
这就是我所说的天真
stream solution. What we do here
流解决方案。我们在这里做什么
is to, again, create the input stream
再次创建输入流
from lines read from the file. But this time,
从文件中读取的行。但是这次
because we're looking for the longest line in the file I thought ok,
因为我们正在寻找我认为可以的文件中的最长行，
let's sort all of the lines
让我们对所有行进行排序
in the file by length. We use a simple Lambda expression
在文件中按长度排列。我们使用一个简单的Lambda表达式
to represent the Comparator so x and y are strings
代表比较器，所以x和y是字符串
and we're just returning the difference in length between
我们只是返回之间的长度差
x and y. By doing it that way around we're sorting based
x和y。通过这种方式，我们可以基于
on longest line will be the first in the sorted list.
最长的行将是排序列表中的第一行。
We can then pass that to findFirst
然后我们可以将其传递给findFirst
which will simply return the first element
这将简单地返回第一个元素
of the input stream, which will be the longest line in the file.
输入流的长度，它将是文件中的最长行。
Then again, because that returns an Optional we use get
再说一次，因为这返回了Optional，我们使用get
to extract the value from that and return it as a string.
从中提取值并将其作为字符串返回。
This is good, so we've solved the problem,
很好，所以我们已经解决了这个问题，
we've used a functional approach
我们使用了函数性方法
and we've solved the problem. No state maintained it's all good. Well,
我们已经解决了这个问题。没有国家维持一切都很好。好，
yes, not really. The problem with this is that by sorting
是的，不是真的。问题是通过排序
all the lines in the file if we have a big file
如果文件很大，文件中的所有行
then it's going to take a long time and it's going to take a lot of resources,
那么这将需要很长时间，并且将需要大量资源，
because the overhead of doing that sorting is going to be quite
因为这样做的开销会相当大
substantial.
实质性的。
I thought there must be a better approach to this; a
我认为必须有一种更好的方法；一种
better functional approach, so let's look at how we find that.
更好的函数方法，让我们看看我们如何找到它。
The first thing I did was I went back and said, ok,
我做的第一件事是回去说，好的，
how I solve this if I was just going to use Java
如果我只是要使用Java，我该如何解决
without being functional? This is the kind of approach we would use.
没有函数？这是我们将要使用的方法。
We have a variable called longest which we
我们有一个叫做longest的变量
initialize to be an empty string. Then we repeatedly read lines from the file
初始化为空字符串。然后我们反复读取文件中的行
using while loop until there are no more lines
使用while循环，直到没有更多的行
to read. Each line that we have, that we read from the file,
读书。从文件中读取的每一行，
compare the length of that string to
比较该字符串的长度为
our current longest line, and if it's longer
我们目前的最长线，如果更长
then we simply record it. At the end
然后我们简单地记录下来。在末尾
we're going to have the longest line in the file. When you look at that
我们将在文件中保留最长的行。当你看着那个
you think, well that's 4 lines of code, great, a really simple solution.
您认为，那是四行代码，非常棒，一个非常简单的解决方案。
Why do I need a functional approach? The answer is
为什么需要函数性方法？答案是
yes it is simple but, it's inherently serial.
是的，它很简单，但是它本质上是串行的。
This goes back to beginning of lesson 1
这可以回到第一课的开始
when we talked about why we needed Lambda expressions because we need a
当我们谈论为什么需要Lambda表达式时，因为我们需要一个
simpler way
更简单的方法
of approaching functional programming in Java. The problem is
Java中进行函数式编程的概念。问题是
this is serial. Yes, we're reading lines from a file,
这是连续的。是的，我们正在从文件中读取行，
we had a large set of data in a list, an ArrayList
我们在列表中有大量数据，即ArrayList
then we might want to process it in parallel to improve efficiency but
那么我们可能希望并行处理它以提高效率，但是
we can't do that with this approach in our code.
我们无法在代码中使用这种方法来做到这一点。
Similarly, because we have a variable
同样，因为我们有一个变量
we now no longer thread safe; we've got mutable
我们现在不再线程安全；我们变了
state. So we need a different approach we need
州。所以我们需要一种不同的方法
a functional approach, but without doing something like a sort.
一种实用的方法，但没有做类似的事情。
Again, if you remember
再说一次，如果你还记得
the beginning of lesson 2 we talked about differences between functional
第2课的开始，我们讨论了函数之间的差异
programming and imperative programming
编程和命令式编程
and the way that functional programming
以及函数式编程的方式
approaches repeated operations is not through using an explicit loop.
处理重复操作不是通过使用显式循环。
The way that we do that with functional programming is to repeatedly call
我们使用函数式编程的方式是反复调用
functions on the results passed by other functions.
函数对其他函数传递的结果。
So it's more like a recursive approach.
因此，它更像是一种递归方法。
We can use that approach in terms of our code. What
我们可以在代码方面使用该方法。什么
I've got here is a method that will recursively
我到这里是一种将递归的方法
solve the problem of finding the longest string. The idea is that we pass in a
解决了找到最长字符串的问题。想法是我们传递一个
string, which is the current longest string that we have,
字符串，这是我们当前拥有的最长字符串，
we pass an index to a list of strings so we know at what point
我们将索引传递给字符串列表，所以我们知道在什么时候
we're in terms of the search and then we pass in the list.
我们在搜索方面，然后传递列表。
The recursive approach will split things up so we take
递归方法会分解事物，所以我们采取
the first string in our list
列表中的第一个字符串
based on where the index is and we compare it to
根据索引的位置，我们将其与
the longest string of the rest of the list.
列表其余部分中最长的字符串。
That calls the method recursively and we can solve the problem. If you
这将递归调用该方法，我们可以解决问题。如果你
wanted to use that
想用那个
it will be a little bit tricky to do it directly from the file; we could probably
直接从文件中进行操作会有些棘手；我们可能
use memory mapping to do that, but it will be quite involved.
使用内存映射来做到这一点，但这会涉及到很多。
A simpler way is simply to read all the lines into an ArrayList
一种更简单的方法是将所有行读入ArrayList
and then use that as our
然后用它作为我们的
list that we pass into our method. We start with an empty string, we
列表，我们将其传递给我们的方法。我们从一个空字符串开始，
start with position 0 in our list and then
从列表中的位置0开始，然后
the method will be called recursively and we'll find
该方法将被递归调用，我们将发现
longest string. This is good.
最长的字符串。很好
So that no explicit loop, we've got no mutable state,
这样就没有显式循环，我们没有可变状态，
so we have a functional solution. In theory,
所以我们有一个函数解决方案。理论上，
well, unfortunately, the problem with this is not really a usable one
好吧，不幸的是，这并不是一个真正可用的问题
because if we had large set of data firstly we are
因为如果我们首先拥有大量数据，
going to read all that data from the file into
将从文件中读取所有数据
an ArrayList, so we need to make sure we've got as much memory as
一个ArrayList，所以我们需要确保拥有尽可能多的内存
the size the file.
文件大小。
But then we're also going to create a new stack frame
但是接下来我们还要创建一个新的堆栈框架
for every line in the file. We're going to call recursively
文件中的每一行。我们将递归调用
generate new stack frame for every line. That's more than likely, if we've got a
为每一行生成新的堆栈框架。如果我们有一个
file of any size going to generate an OutOfMemoryException.
任何大小的文件都会生成OutOfMemoryException。
We will just run out of memory before we can actually process everything.
在实际处理所有内容之前，我们将耗尽内存。
So let's go back to stream API,
让我们回到流API，
which is really what we're trying to do. We're trying to find out how to use
这确实是我们正在尝试做的。我们正在尝试找出使用方法
the stream API to solve this problem and
流API解决此问题，并且
if you look at the stream API we tend to use this well-known pattern
如果您看一下流API，我们倾向于使用这种众所周知的模式
of filter, map, reduce. And in the case of this particular problem
过滤，映射，减少。在这种特殊情况下
we don't need to do any filtering, because we're looking for the longest
我们不需要进行任何过滤，因为我们正在寻找最长的过滤器
line
线
in the file, so we're not trying to
在文件中，因此我们不尝试
reduce that in terms that we're not trying to eliminate any of the data
根据我们不试图消除任何数据的观点来减少这种情况
to create subset. We also don't need to use map,
创建子集。我们也不需要使用地图，
because we're not trying to convert from anything, we're simply interested in
因为我们不尝试从任何东西转换，我们只是对
each of the lines and whichever is the longest. So all we're interested in here
每条线，以最长的一条为准。所以我们对这里感兴趣
is reduce and
是减少和
if we recall the actual definition of the reduce method from
如果我们回想起reduce方法的实际定义，
earlier in the course we'll see that
在课程的早期，我们将看到
the reduce method takes an accumulator
reduce方法需要累加器
as a parameter and the accumulator is
作为参数，累加器是
a binary operator and, again, remember back when we talked about the
一个二元运算符，再一次，当我们谈到
functional interfaces that been included in the
包含在
java.util.function package, BinaryOperator
java.util.function软件包，BinaryOperator
is in effect a BiFunction where
实际上是BiFunction，其中
you got two inputs and an output where all the types
您有两个输入和一个输出，其中所有类型
are of the same so we going to take two inputs
是相同的，所以我们将接受两个输入
and generate an output of the same type. The
并生成相同类型的输出。的
output of the final reduce is an Optional.
final reduce的输出是可选的。
What we need to do to solve this problem is to find
我们需要做的就是解决这个问题
the right accumulator, so we need to determine what is the correct
正确的蓄能器，所以我们需要确定什么是正确的
BinaryOperator, where we take two inputs and generate an
BinaryOperator，我们接受两个输入并生成一个
output in order to solve the problem. Again, if we go back to looking at the reduce
输出以解决问题。再说一次，如果我们回到看减少
method definition what we find is
我们发现的方法定义是
that the accumulator is described as something which takes the partial result
累加器被描述为需要部分结果的东西
and the next element and returns a new partial result.
和下一个元素，并返回新的部分结果。
In effect what it's doing is the same as a recursive solution.
实际上，它的作用与递归解决方案相同。
So it's saying to take the
所以说要
first element of the stream and compare against
流的第一个元素，并与之进行比较
that and determine which is the longest of those lines.
并确定哪一条是最长的。
Which obviously is that the first one and then we'll compare against the rest.
显然这是第一个，然后我们将与其余的进行比较。
So we then apply the function again,
因此，我们再次应用该函数，
where we say to take the next element and compare
我们说要接受下一个元素并进行比较
against our partial result, which is the longest line we've found so far.
相对于我们的部分结果，这是我们到目前为止找到的最长的线。
We can effectively apply this reduce operation multiple times, or the
我们可以多次有效地应用这种减少操作，或者
accumulator operation multiple times for each line.
每行多次执行累加器操作。
We're processing the partial result against the
我们正在针对
next string in our input stream. We don't have all
输入流中的下一个字符串。我们没有全部
the stack frames because internally this is not being done through
堆栈帧，因为在内部这不是通过
an actual recursion, so we don't have to worry about the
实际的递归，所以我们不必担心
impact on performance. What we end up with them
对性能的影响。我们最终得到了什么
is the solution. Same idea, we're taking the lines
是解决方案。相同的想法，我们在排队
read from the file and this time we're passing it to
从文件读取，这次我们将其传递给
out reduce method. This is a terminal operation, so it
减少方法。这是终端操作，所以
won't return another stream and the
不会返回其他流，并且
the function that we're going to use in terms of that
我们将要使用的函数
takes two inputs: x and y which
接受两个输入：x和y
are strings and then compares the length for those strings and
是字符串，然后比较这些字符串的长度和
returns whichever is the longest. The key thing here
返回最长的那个。这里的关键
is X, because in this case
是X，因为在这种情况下
X is effectively maintaining the state for us
X有效地维持着我们的状态
but always holding the longest string that we've found so far.
但始终保留到目前为止我们发现的最长的字符串。
This is our partial result.
这是我们的部分结果。
So as we read the elements on the input stream,
因此，当我们读取输入流上的元素时，
X is always going to represent the longest string that we've found so far
X总是代表我们到目前为止找到的最长的字符串
in the input stream, y is going to be
在输入流中，y将是
the next element in the input stream. So we're simply comparing the
输入流中的下一个元素。所以我们只是比较
longest as we've found so far with the
到目前为止，我们发现的时间最长
next element and determining whether the new partial result
下一个元素并确定新的部分结果是否
is the current one or the
是当前的还是
string that we just read. Now
我们刚刚读取的字符串。现在
I showed this to an engineer in our team and he said, ah yes, that's very good,
我向团队中的工程师展示了这一点，他说，是的，非常好，
but there's actually a simpler solution, because you can use
但实际上有一个更简单的解决方案，因为您可以使用
max. Remember max is just a specialized form
最高请记住，max只是一种特殊形式
over reduction but we also have another form of max
过度减少，但我们还有另一种形式的max
where you can pass a Comparator as a parameter.
您可以在其中传递比较器作为参数。
We end up with simple solution where we can simply say
我们最终得到了简单的解决方案，我们可以简单地说
take the lines from a file as our stream source
将文件中的行作为流源
and pass that to max which uses
并将其传递给使用
a function, in this case it's ToIntFunction
一个函数，在这种情况下是ToIntFunction
so that will generate integers as results
这样会生成整数作为结果
based on what we want to do in this case it's going to be
根据我们在这种情况下想要做的
using length of the strings. So ComparingInt is a
使用字符串的长度。所以ComparingInt是一个
static method on Comparator we can simply convert strings into lengths
比较器上的静态方法，我们可以简单地将字符串转换为长度
and then we will compare our strings
然后我们将比较字符串
based on length and return the maximum of those.
根据长度返回最大的那些。
And then again that returns an Optional so
然后再次返回一个Optional，所以
we can get the results from that. But the important thing here
我们可以从中得到结果。但是重要的是
is to understand that what we're doing is
是要了解我们正在做的是
using reduction. To take the stream and
使用减少。顺流而下
reduce it to a single value and
将其减少为单个值，然后
the way that the reduction works is defined
定义减少工作的方式
by the accumulator. The accumulator
由累加器。蓄能器
is BinaryOperator, so it's one that takes two inputs
是BinaryOperator，所以它需要两个输入
and returns an output all of the same type.
并返回所有相同类型的输出。
And the accumulator is applied successively to stream elements,
然后将累加器依次应用于流元素，
so it gives us the effective recursive
所以它给我们有效的递归
operation that we've seen in the past. The reduce method
我们过去看到的操作。减少方法
maintains the partial result as state,
保持部分结果为状态，
but we don't see that explicitly, so we don't need to worry about it.
但是我们没有明确看到它，因此我们不必担心。
The important thing to take away from this part of the lesson is that you do
从本节课中摘取的重要内容是
need to think differently. You need to stop thinking in terms of loops,
需要换个角度思考。您需要停止思考循环，
explicit loops, you need to stop thinking in terms of explicit
显式循环，您需要停止对显式循环的思考
state and move to the idea of
陈述并转向
chaining together method calls having,
将方法调用链接在一起，
in effect, we could achieve recursive processing in order to give you this
实际上，我们可以实现递归处理，以便为您提供
approach of
的方法
how you repeatedly process data. And that is the end
您如何重复处理数据。到此为止
of section 1 of this lesson.
本节第1部分的内容。